American Textile Machinery Association Photographs 6507 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Textile Machinery Association Photographs
1964-1965
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Textile Machinery Association (ATMA)
6507 P
1 folders
1 file folder
Gelatin silver print, photographs.
Images from the Annual Meetings of the ATMA for 1964 and 1965.
10062376
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 06, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 07, 2017
Scope and Contents
Images depict the officers of the ATMA: Robert S. Pennock (President), James H. Hunter (Incoming President), Edward C. Connor (Treasurer), and the heads of various textile machinery manufacturers. Also pictured are political figures such as the governor of South Carolina, Donald Russell, the former governor of North Carolina, Luther H. Hodges, and the Deputy to the Secretary of Commerce, James S. Love, Jr.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6605 G: Davis & Furber Machine Company Graphics 6605/001: Davis & Furber Machine Company General Records 6750 G: Leonard Windle Collection of Textile Related Graphics 6750 P: Leonard Windle Collection of Textile Related Photographs
Management; Textile machinery industry -- Management; Textile machinery industry -- Congresses; Charlotte (N.C.); Greenville (S.C.); Andrews, Mildred Gwin, 1903-1984.; Connor, Edward C.; Daniel, Hank; Hodges, Luther Hartwell, 1898-1974.; Hunter, J. H. (James H.); Jordan, Joe F.; Love, James S.; Pennock, Robert S.; Russell, Donald Stuart, 1906-1998.; Stern, Robert.; American Textile Machinery Association -- Management; American Textile Machinery Association -- Congresses
10062376
- 31st Annual Meeting and 32nd Annual Meeting, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  February 26, 1964 and March 3, 1965.
  - Item 1: Members of the Board and Directors of American Textile Machinery Association and ATMA Exhibition Committee, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C. Image depicts eleven men and one woman, members of the ATMA, seated around a table as they review the status of the ATMA Exhibition-International '65. Plans of exhibitor space on easels in the back of the room. Left to right: P. Kay Schwartz, pres. Proctor & Schwartz, Philadelphia; Thomas H. West, pres. Draper Corp., Hopedale, Mass.; John H. Bolton Jr., vp Whitin Machine Works, Whitinsville, Mass.; Robert E. Borchardt, vp Barber-Colman Co., Rockford, Ill.; Robert Leeson, pres. Leesona Corp., Warwick R.I.; James H. Hunter, pres. ATMA, pres. James Hunter Machine Co., North Adams, Mass.; Robert S. Pennock, immediate past pres. ATMA, vp Leesona Corp.; Edward C. Connor, treas. ATMA, reg. sales mgr., Whitin Machine Works; Herman K. Jennings, sales mgr. Warner & Swasey Co., Cleveland; John P. Franklin, pres. David Gessner Co., Worcester, Mass.; Arthur W. Reynolds, pres. & treas., Davis & Furber Machine Co., North Andover, Mass.; Mildred Gwin Andrews, exec. sec., ATMA. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
    Format: Black and White photograph.
  - Item 2: Robert Stern and Robert Pennock, 31st annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1964; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts Robert Stern (on the left), consultant to the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Science and Technology, U.S. Dept. of Commerce, Washington, D.C., chatting with Robert S. Pennock, president of ATMA, and vice president of Leesona Corporation, Warwick, R.I., at the 31st annual meeting of ATMA, Feb. 2, 1964, in Charlotte, N.C. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 3: James S. Love Jr. and Robert Pennock, 31st annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1964; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Hank Daniel, photographer. Image depicts James S. Love Jr. (on the left), the deputy to the Secretary of Commerce, Washington, D.C., and speaker at the luncheon session, Myers Park Country Club, chatting at lunch with Robert S. Pennock, president of ATMA, and vice president of Leesona Corporation, Warwick, R.I., at the 31st annual meeting of ATMA, Feb. 2, 1964, in Charlotte, N.C. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 4: Robert S. Pennock at the podium, 31st Annual Meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1964; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Hank Daniel, photographer. Image depicts Robert S. Pennock, president of the ATMA and vice president of Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I., at the podium introducing the luncheon speaker, James S. Love Jr. (on the left), the deputy to the Secretary of Commerce, Washington, D.C., at the 31st annual meeting of the ATMA, February 26, 1964, Myers Park Country Club, Charlotte, N.C. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 5: Robert S. Pennock at the podium, 31st annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1964; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Hank Daniel, photographer. Image depicts Robert S. Pennock, president of the ATMA and vice president of Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I., at the podium introducing the luncheon speaker, James S. Love Jr. (on the left), the deputy to the Secretary of Commerce, Washington, D.C., at the 31st annual meeting of the ATMA, February 26, 1964, Myers Park Country Club, Charlotte, N.C. Very similar, but not identical to, 1993.75.4. 20.5 x 25.5 cm.
  - Item 6: Edward C. Connor, James H. Hunter, and Robert S. Pennock, 32nd annual Board of Directors meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C. Image depicts (l to r): Edward C. Connor, ATMA treasurer and regional sales manager, Whitin Machine Works, Whitinsville, Mass.; James H. Hunter, incoming ATMA president and president, James Hunter Machine Co., North Adams, Mass; and Robert S. Pennock, ATMA president and vice president, Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I. Plans for exhibitor space at the ATMA Exhibition-International '65 in background. Meeting held March 2, 1965 at Greenville, S.C. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 7: Robert S. Pennock addressing the 32nd annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C. Image depicts Robert S. Pennock, ATMA president and vice president, Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I., at the podium, speaking at the 32nd annual meeting of the ATMA held March 3, 1965 at Greenville, S.C. 20.5 x 25.5 cm.
  - Item 8: Luther H. Hodges speaking at the 32nd annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C. Image depicts Luther H. Hodges, former governor of North Carolina, retired Ssecretary of Commerce, and chairman, N.C. Research Triangle Foundation, speaking at the podium at the 32nd annual meeting of the ATMA held March 3, 1965 at Greenville, S.C. On the left is Robert S. Pennock, ATMA president and vice president of Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 9: Donald Russell, Luther H. Hodges, James H. Hunter, Robert S. Pennock at 32nd annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C. Image depicts (l to r) Donald Russell, governor of South Carolina; Luther H. Hodges, former governor of North Carolina; James H. Hunter, incoming president of the ATMA and president, James Hunter Machine Co., North Adams, Mass.; and Robert S. Pennock, outgoing president of ATMA and vice president, Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I., at the 32nd annual meeting of the ATMA held March 3, 1965 at Greenville, S.C. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 10: James H. Hunter at podium, 32nd annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C. Image depicts James H. Hunter, the new president of ATMA and president, James Hunter Machine Co., North Adams, Mass., at the podium at the 32nd annual meeting of ATMA, held March 3, 1965 at Greenville, S.C. On the left are Luther H. Hodges, former governor of North Carolina, and Robert S. Pennock (exchanging gift with Hunter), outgoing president of ATMA and vice president, Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I. 25.25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 11: James H. Hunter at podium, 32nd annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C. Image depicts James H. Hunter, the new president of ATMA and president, James Hunter Machine Co., North Adams, Mass., at the podium at the 32nd annual meeting of ATMA, held March 3, 1965 at Greenville, S.C. On the left are Luther H. Hodges, former governor of North Carolina, and Robert S. Pennock, outgoing president of ATMA and vice president, Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I. Very similar but not identical to 1993.75.10. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 12: Luther H. Hodges and Robert S. Pennock, 32nd annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C. Image depicts Luther H. Hodges, former governor of North Carolina (second from left) and Robert S. Pennock, outgoing president of ATMA and vice president, Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I. (third from left) at the 32nd annual meeting of ATMA, held March 3, 1965 at Greenville, S.C. Woman on the left and man at the podium are unidentified. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 13: Members of ATMA at 32nd annual meeting of the American Textile Machinery Association, 1965; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Joe F. Jordan, Photographer, Greenville, S.C.? Image depicts (l to r): James S. Love Jr., deputy to the Secretary of Commerce, Washington, D.C., and speaker at meeting; Robert S. Pennock, outgoing president of ATMA and vice president, Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I.; Edward C. Connor, treasurer, ATMA, and regional sales manager, Whitin Machine Works, Whitinsville, Mass.; James H. Hunter, new ATMA president and president, James Hunter Machine Co., North Adams, Mass.; and Mildred Gwin Andrews (?), executive secretary, ATMA, at the 32nd annual meeting of ATMA, held March 3, 1965 at Greenville, S.C. 25.25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 14: Board of Directors, American Textile Machinery Association, 1964; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts the officers and board of directors, taken at the 31st annual meeting of the ATMA, in Charlotte, N.C., Feb. 26, 1964. Standing left to right: John H. Bolton Jr., VP, Whitin Machine Works, Whitinsville, Mass.; Robert Pomeranz, President, Roberts Company, Sanford, N.C.: James H. Hunter, VP ATMA, and President, Textile Machinery Division, Crompton & Knowles Corp., Worcester, Mass.; Robert S. Pennock, President, ATMA, and VP Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I.; Arthur W. Reynolds, Director, Davis & Furber Machine Co., North Andover, Mass.; John W. Powischill, VP, Proctor & Schwartz, Inc.; Robert Leeson, President, Leesona Corp., Warwick, R.I.; Thomas H. West, President, Draper Corp., Hopedale, Mass.; Herman K. Jennings, Sales Manager, Textile Div., Warner & Swasey Co., Cleveland, Ohio; Robert E. Borchardt, Manager, Textile Machinery Div., Barber-Colman Co., Rockford, Ill. Seated left to right: Norman F. Garrett, President, Whitin Machine Works; John P. Franklin, President, David Gessner Co., Worcester, Mass.; Mildred Gwin Andrews, Executive Secretary, ATMA and Manager of American Textile Machinery Exhibition-International; Russell Graham, President, Saco-Lowell Shops, Easley, S.C.: Edward C. Connor, Treasurer, ATMA and President, Foster Machine Co., Westfield, Mass. Copy B. 25.25 x 20.5 cm.